MOHAMED BILAL K

SENTOR APPAREL MERCHANDISER

+91 7845053499 kmohamedbilal3@gmail.com | Tirupur



A versatile, enthusiastic and dedicated professional with expansive knowledge in the field of merchandising. An adept Team-Player willing to utilize my skillset to the fullest, learn and grow within an organization. Merchandiser with vast knowledge on fabrics, processing and finishing techniques. Over the years, I've acquired the needed ability to handle challenges & work under pressure with a presence of mind, logical thinking and in a composed manner.

CAREER SUMMARY

Energetic, deadline driven professional with 5+ years in merchandising, buyer communication & sample development. Highly motivated to stay updated with the current market/seasonal trends. Flexible & adaptive to the customer's buying needs. Can work swiftly & efficiently under pressure. Strategic planning & execution of the planned task are my strengths.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Project Manager Advanced Clothing Concepts, Coimbatore | Feb, 2023 -Present

- Delivering compelling products, businesses captivating brand experiences, developing Functional Clothing based on the understanding of Workwear, the importance of innovation in work attire and the need for new concepts in the field.
- Experience in handling Clients such has Yamaha, Colgate, Hyundai, MTR, Podaran Joyalukkas, Philips, Bangalore International Airport (BIAL).
- Communicating with the buyers to understand their reguirements and provide clarity on product development.
- In depth review and making of techpacks/ style sheets required for clients.
- Sourcing and programming for the required raw materials at the right time span for the right quantity in the right price.



- Creating BOM and accessory requirement plan.
- Coordinating with the vendors and clients simultaneously.
- Planning and initiating sample development
- Bulk order schedule planning and follow up
- Lead Time Maintenance.
- Handling small quantities, novel and niche products.
- Worked extensively across various Workwear Products.

Senior Merchandiser ASM Knitwear Pvt. Ltd., Tirupur | Feb,2019 - Present

- Handled Buyers Retour (The Netherlands), MLLNR (The Netherlands), Add To Bag (Denmark), Seek n Hide (The Netherlands), Hound (Denmark).
- Communicating with the buyers to understand their requirements and provide clarity on product development.
- In depth review of techpacks/ style sheets sent by the buyers.
- Sourcing and programming for the required raw materials at the right time span for the right quantity in the right price.
- Creating BOM and accessory requirement plan.
- Coordinating with the vendors and buyers simultaneously.

Assistant Merchandiser AGR Apparels, Tirupur | Apr, 2017 - Jan, 2019

- Handled Buyer Ellepi (Italy).
- Gathered hands on experience on product development and sourcing.
- Working knowledge of various styles across apparel categories.
- Coordinating with the team as well as the suppliers on all aspects.
- Providing weekly updates and maintaining consistency in day-to-day duties and responsibilities.
- Providing inputs in pattern making, sample development and assisting in bulk order follow up.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Sequence of operations
- Fabrics & trims sourcing
- Costing & negotiation
- Sample development & order follow-up
- Supplier coordination
- Communication with the buyers

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Planning & Organizing
- Decision making
- Willingness to learn
- Adaptability
- Resilience
- Communication

INTERESTS

- Sports
- Automobiles
- Food connoisseur
- Photography
- Gadgets
- Travelling

EDUCATION

- Diploma in Mechanical Engineering
 2016The Salem Polytechnic
 College, Salem
- SSLC 2013 Sri Gayathri Higher Secondary School, Salem